Hello and welcome to Real easy English We're back with another conversation in easyasy English to help you learn I'm Georgie and I'm Phil and you can find a video
Version of this podcast with subtitles to help you on our website and that's atbblearningenglish.com. .
Hello Phil, how are you I'm I'm good but I'm also a little bit tired because I've been doing DIY all weekend
Well that's lucky because today when talking about DIY DY stands for do it yourself and it means doing things to your home
Such as fixing and painting so what kind of DIY have you been doing this weekend Yes I've been trying,
To fix my water tankOkay, and do you do a lot of DIY more than I want to
, um I'm not very good at DIy.
If it's something I can do, I will try and do it some things I would never touch like electrics,
I wouldn't go anywhere near that or gas because it's not safe, but, If it's something that looks safe and I think I can do it,
I will try it Okay, so what kinds of things do you do around the house?
It could be things like painting and decorating a house, making it look nice at that I quite like I can do that sometimes fixing things with bits of wood.
That need to go somewhere, I can do that, um putting up fences,
I can do that, but that's probably it What about you, Georgie, do you do much DiIy?
No, I don't.
I actually rent my flat, so that means I can't really do much to the place because it's not mine but recently I have put up some.
Lights in my room because I changed rooms.
So I've put up some nice fairy lights on the wall, and I've put up some frames with art and photos.
So that's probably my limit, I wouldn't do anything else Do you enjoy DIY?
No, I don't because I'm quite a lazy person, so if I see that something is broken or needs fixing,
I will just ignore it, procrastinate, which means to delay something, postpone it.
Um and wait for someone else to do it I kind of get used to things being broken and forget that it's like thatum so yeah'm
I'm just a bit lazy Phil have you ever, Put together furniture like flat pack furniture, Yes, yes, I've done that Yeah, quite a lotum because.
Yeah, a lot of furniture you buy that's fairly cheap, you have to do thatum I don't actually mind that I quite like that it's
Quite good to do it with someone.
And you work as a team like an activity.
Yes, yes, it can.
Well, sometimes it's fun, sometimes it's stressful.
Yeah, if it goes well, that can be a nice thing to do with someone, but.
If it goes badly, it could lead to an argument.
Do you have any big plans for your house, I would really like to get a very nice bit of wood and make a nice bar for my kitchen.
I'd love to do that but it's expensive and I haven't done it yet I keep procrastinating and not doing it What about you I rent my flat so I can't do anything
Big I don't have big plans, but we do have.
An outdoorterrace which at the moment it's not very, it's not in a very good state, so I would like to clean it, maybe get some plants for it.
I'd like to put some lights out there actually, so that when people come round, it will be really nice in the evenings so yeah that's my plan ready for the summer
That sounds lovely.
Okay,
Let's recap the language we heard during the conversation, starting with DIY, which stands for do it yourself.
These are jobs you do around the house like fixing or painting for example, I don't like DiIY I'm too lazy We also heard decorate which means paint
A room or change how it looks.
We heard flat pack furniture, which is furniture, which comes with instructions so that you can build it yourself and we heard a couple of phrasal verbs
If you put something up, You fix it to the wall so for example, Georgie put up some picture frames in her bedroom and if you put something together,
You build it for example, Phil likes to put together flat pack furniture with someone else.
And that's it for this episode of real easy English, you can practice what you've learned with a worksheet that's on our website, bbclearningenglish.com. .
And we'll be back next week with another conversation in easyasy English, goodbye for now, bye.